Thank you.
I don't need one.
I got a good phone.
Good morning.
It took a minute to get the roll going this morning.
Okay.
I got it over here, but I'm going to need to put these on the way.
This is out of the stash and accompanies those extra ones.
Okay.
Does he have the sparring?
Yes.
.
Thank you.
man frigid so should i start with one of these guys yeah yeah yeah start with
yeah six and it's going to have a little i didn't take these
and then what i was interested in is open that one up where the game control is where the batteries
are let's see where that one's set yeah this one's set almost at full you see a little arrow
It's like one o'clock.
Okay, I see this comes out back a little bit.
Okay.
Just go back to the scene.
Should we do that for the rest of the room?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Just one o'clock.
Yeah.
Just so we're at the same reference.
Take all of the, all of the, for lack of a better word,
because it ties up here.
Okay.
Set it over there.
That is what this little squishy comes in.
If you don't want to use the squishy, you can put it in there to keep it nice.
This helps when someone says the letter P or T.
It doesn't make that popping sound through the microphone.
That little piece of phone does that.
Yeah.
complosives.
Consensibles.
That's a good question.
Sophia's full of them.
All bad?
Oh, yeah.
Good questions.
They're good.
She's 50% good questions, 50% attitude.
Okay, well, that's okay, too, as long as it's focused correctly.
It will be.
I'm Michael by the way, Sophia right?
Hi Michael.
Hello, I'm Michael.
Okay.
Let's start with six.
Let me just see.
So I can just turn it on.
Can I just push it?
Yeah.
Go ahead.
Test.
Test one, two.
Hello?
Testing one, two.
Test one two.
Hang on.
Testing one two.
Enna, vio.
One two.
Test one two.
Enna.
Okay.
Let's see here.
Oh
Τότε κάτι ήλθες προς τον θάνατον η ζωή αθάνατος, τότε τον άδεινε νέκρος σας,
η άστραπη της θεότητος, τότε δε και του στεθνεώτας εκ των κατακθονίων ανέστησας.
Πάσε δυνάμι στον επουρανή
Μπορείς άλλη λίγο.
Okay.
Test 1-2
Do you want me to
I'll just chant
Okay
The Holy Spirit is the Holy Spirit, the Holy Spirit is the Holy Spirit.
ο ερχόμενος εν ονόματι Κυρίου.
Θεός Κυρίος και επεφάνεν ημιν ευλογημένος
Των λίθων του μνήματος φράγι στην εμικολύσσας
Την πέτρα αντίθεση
7-8.
Μετά το πάθος πορεύθησε εν το μνήματι, προς το μυρίσε το σώμα σου, εγινέκες Χριστέ ο Θεός,
Είδω να γένουσεν το τάφο και εξέστησαν φωνείς γαρίκου ορακού.
εξ αυτών ότι άνεστη ο Κύριος.
Εν το ουράνο τα ώματα εκπέμπω μου της καρδίας προς σε σωτήρ σ' όσον με ση επιλάμψη,
ελέησον ημάς τους πτέοντας η πόλα, κάθε κά στην ουραν ο Χριστέ μου,
και δώσ' προτελούς τρόπους του μετανοήνση,
πόξα πατρίδινση.
και Υιώ και Αγίου.
Σαρτά από τον Άμιν.
Δόξα Πατρί και Υιώ και Αγίου Πνεύματι,
και νυν και αϊκέ εις τους αιώνας των αιώνων,
Αγίοι ο Πνεύματι το βασιλεύει
Αγίοι ο Πνεύματι το βασιλεύειν πέλη, το αγιάζειν το κοινήν την κτίσην,
Θεός γαρέστην, όμως ή ως πατρή και λόγο.
Υμοι ότι κύριος είναι ημιν της ικανός ο
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Hello.
Αυτό.
Ο Θεός ειλάσθητη με το αμαρτωλό κελέησον με.
Ευλογητός ο Θεός ημών πάντοτε εν ίνθω.
Αμήν.
Άγιος ο Θεός, Άγιος Ισχυρός, Άγιος Αθάνατος, ελέησον ημάς
Άγιος ο Θεός, Άγιος Ισχυρός, Άγιος Αθάνατος, ελέησον ημάς.
Δόξα Πατρί και Υιό και Αγίο Πνεύματι, και νυν και αΐ και εις τους αιώνας των αιώνων αμήν.
Παναγία Τριάς, ελέησον ημάς.
Κύριε ηλάσθη διδεσαι αμαρτίες ημών, δέσποτα συγχώρησον τα σανομία σιμήν.
Άγιοι επίσκεψε και ίασε τα σασθενεία σιμών
Ένεκεν του όνοματός σου
Κύριε Λέισον, Κύριε Λέισον
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Αλλά ρίσσε ημάς από του πονηρού.
Ό,τι σου εστίνει η Βασιλεία και η δύναμης και η δόξα
του Πατρός και του Υιού και του Αγίου Πνεύματος
νυν και αι και εις τους αιώνας των αιώνων.
Αμήν. Σώσον Κύριε των λαών σου και ευλόγισον την πληρονομίαν σου.
Νίκας της βασιλεύσης κατά βαρβάρων δουρούμενος
και τοσών φυλάτων δια του σταυρού σου πολίτευμα.
Δόξα Πατρί και Υιόγειο.
και Αγίο Πνεύματι, ο υψωθής εν το σταυρό
εκουσίως, τη επωνύμου σου καινή πολιτεία
του συκτηρμού σου τόρισε Χριστέ ο Θεός
έφρανον εν τη δυνάμι σου τους πιστούς βασιλείς ημών
νίκας χορηγών αυτής κατά των πολεμίων
την συμμαχίαν έχει εν την συν όπλων ειρήνης
αείτη των τρόπαιων και νίν και αεί και εις τους αιώνας των αιώνων
αμήν. Προστασία φοβερά και άκατέσκυνται
μη παρήδεις γαθήτας και ασίασημων
Πανείμνητε Θεοτόκε, στήριξε Ορθοδόξων Πολιτείαν, σώζε...
Have mercy on us, O God, according to your great mercy.
We pray to you, hear us and have mercy.
Lord, have mercy, Lord, have mercy, Lord, have mercy.
Let us pray for pious and orthodox Christians.
Again we pray for our Father and Archbishop Nick.
Nicholas, and all our brotherhood in Christ.
For you are a merciful God who loves mankind,
and to you we offer up glory,
to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit,
now and forever, and to the ages of ages.
Amen. In the name of the Lord, Father, bless.
Glory to the holy, consubstantial life-giving,
an undivided Trinity always.
now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
Glory to God in the highest
and on earth peace goodwill among men.
O Lord, you shall open my lips
and my mouth will declare your praise.
O Lord, why do those who afflict me multiply?
Many are those who rise up against me.
Many are those who say to my soul, there is no salvation for him and his God.
But you, O Lord, are my protector, my glory, and the one who lifts up my head.
I cried to the Lord with my voice, and he heard me from his holy hill.
I lay down and slept. I awoke, for the Lord will help me.
I will not be afraid of ten thousands of people who set themselves against me all around.
Arise, O Lord, and save me, O my God, for you struck all those who were foolishly at enmity with me.
You broke the teeth of sinners. Salvation is of the Lord, and your blessing is upon your people.
I lay down and slept, I awoke, for the Lord will help me.
O Lord, do not rebuke me in your wrath, nor chasten me in your anger.
For your arrows are fixed in me, and your hand rests on me.
There is no healing in my flesh because of your wrath.
There is no peace in my bones because of my sins.
For my transgressions rise up over my head.
Like a heavy burden, they are heavy on me.
My wounds grow foul and fester because of my folly.
I suffer misery. I am utterly bowed down.
I go all the day long with a sad face.
for my loins are filled with mockeries
and there is no healing in my flesh.
I am afflicted and greatly humbled.
I roar because of the groaning of my heart.
O Lord, all my desire is before you,
and my groaning is not hidden from you.
My heart is troubled, my strength fails me,
and the light of my eyes, even this is not with me.
My friends and neighbors draw near and stand against me,
and my near of kin stand far off.
And those who seek my soul use violence,
and those who seek evil for me speak folly,
and they meditate on deceit all the day long.
But I, like a deaf man, do not hear,
and I am like a mute who does not
He says,
love as though it were a stinking corpse. Do not forsake me, O Lord, my God. Do not depart from me.
Give heed to help me, O Lord, of my salvation. Do not forsake me, O Lord, O my God. Do not depart
from me. Give heed to help me, O Lord, of my salvation. O God, my God, I rise early to be with
you. My soul thirsts for you. How often my flesh thirsts for you in a desolate, impassable, and
waterless land. So in the holy place I appear before you to see your power and your glory.
because your mercy is better than life.
My lips shall praise you.
Thus I will bless you in my life. I will lift up my hands in your name.
May my soul be filled as with marrow and fatness,
and my mouth shall sing praise to you with lips filled with rejoicing.
If I remembered you on my bed, I meditated on you at daybreak,
for you are my helper, and in the shelter of your wings I will greatly rejoice.
My soul follows close behind you, and your right hand takes hold of me.
But they seek for my soul in vain.
They shall go into the lowest parts of the earth.
They shall be given over to the edge of the sword.
They shall be a portion for foxes.
but the king
shall be glad in God. All who swear by him shall be praised, for the mouth that speaks unrighteous
things is stopped. I meditated on you at daybreak, for you are my helper, and in the shelter of your
wings I will greatly rejoice. My soul follows close behind you, your right hand takes hold of me.
Glory to the Father, and the Son, and the Holy Spirit, both now and ever, and to the ages of ages.
Amen. Alleluia, alleluia, alleluia, glory to you, O God. Alleluia, alleluia, alleluia, glory to you,
O God. Alleluia, alleluia, alleluia, glory to you, O God. Lord, have mercy, Lord, have mercy,
you, Lord.
mercy, glory to the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit, both now and ever into the
ages of ages. Amen. O Lord, God of my salvation, I cry day and night before you. Let my prayer
come before you, incline your ear to my supplication, O Lord. For my soul is filled with sorrows
and my soul draws near to Hades. I am counted among those who go down into the pit. I am
like a helpless man, free among the dead, like slain men thrown down and sleeping in
a grave, whom you remember no more, but they are removed from your hand. They laid me in
the lowest pit in dark
places and in the shadow of death. Your wrath rested upon me and you brought all your billows
over me. You removed my acquaintances far from me. They made me an abomination among themselves.
I was betrayed and did not go forth. My eyes weakened from poverty, O Lord. I cried to you
the whole day. I spread out my hands to you. Will you work wonders for the dead? Or will physicians
raise them up and acknowledge you? Shall anyone in the grave describe your mercy and your truth
and destruction? Shall your wonders be known in darkness and your righteousness in a forgotten
But I cried to you, O Lord, and in the morning my parishioners
come near to you. Why, O Lord, do you reject
my soul and turn away your face for me?
I am poor and in troubles for my youth,
but having been exalted, I was humbled
and brought into despair. Your fierce
anger passed over me, and your terrors greatly
troubled me. They compassed me like water
all the day long. They surrounded
me at once. You removed far from
me neighbor and friend and my acquaintances
because of my misery. O Lord, God
of my salvation, I cry day and night before you.
Let my prayer come before you and climb
your ear to my supplication, O Lord.
Bless the Lord, O my soul, and everything within me.
bless his holy name. Bless the Lord, O my soul, and forget not all his rewards, who is merciful to all
your transgressions, who heals all your diseases, who redeems your life from corruption, who crowns
you with mercy and compassion, who satisfies your desire with good things, and your youth is renewed
like the eagles. The Lord shows mercies and judgments to all who are wronged. He made known
his ways to Moses and the things that he willed to the sons of Israel. The Lord is compassionate and
merciful, slow to anger, and abounding in mercy. He will not become angry to the end.
nor will he be wrathful forever.
He did not deal with us according to our sins,
nor reward us according to our transgressions.
For according to the height of heaven from earth,
so the Lord reigns in mercy over those who fear him.
As far as the east is from the west,
so he removes our transgressions from us.
As a father has compassion on his children,
so the Lord has compassion on those who go in fear of him.
For he knows how he formed us, he remembers we are dust.
Man, his days are like grass, as a flower of the field,
so he flourishes.
for the wind passes through it.
and it shall not remain, and it shall no longer know its place.
But the mercy of the Lord is from age to age upon those who fear him,
and his righteousness upon children's children,
to such as keep his covenant and remember his commandments to do them.
The Lord prepared his throne in heaven, and his kingdom rules over all.
Bless the Lord, all you his angels, mighty in strength, who do his word,
so as to hear the voice of his words.
Bless the Lord, all you his hosts, his ministers who do his will.
Bless the Lord, all his works, in all places of his dominion.
and bless the Lord, O my soul.
all places of his dominion. Bless the Lord, O my soul. O Lord, hear my prayer. Give ear to my
supplication in your truth. Answer me in your righteousness, and do not enter into judgment
with your servant, for no one living shall become righteous in your sight. For the enemy persecuted
my soul. He humbled my life to the ground. He caused me to dwell in dark places as one long dead,
and my spirit was in anguish within me. My heart was troubled within me. I remembered the days of
old. I meditated on all your works. I meditated on the works of your hands. I spread out my
hand.
to you. My soul thirsts for you like a waterless land. Hear me speedily, O Lord. My spirit faints
within me. Turn not your face from me, lest I become like those who go down into the pit.
Cause me to hear your mercy in the morning, for I hope in you. Make me know, O Lord, the way wherein
I should walk, for I lift up my soul to you. Deliver me from my enemies, O Lord, for to you I flee for
refuge. Teach me to do your will, for you are my God. Your good spirit shall guide me in the land
of uprightness. For your name's sake, O Lord, give me life. In your righteousness you shall bring my
soul out of affliction.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Doxasio, Theos, Elbis, Simon, Kyrie, doxasio.
In peace, let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For the peace of God and the salvation of our souls,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For peace in the whole world,
for the stability of the holy churches of God,
and for the unity of all, let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For this holy house and for those who enter it,
with faith, reverence, and the fear of God,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For our Father and Archbishop Nicholas,
the Honourable Presbyters,
the deacons in the service of Christ,
and all the clergy and people,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For our country, the President,
and all those in public service,
Thank you.
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For this parish and city,
for every city and country,
and for the faithful who live in them,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For favorable weather and abundance
of the fruits of the earth
and for peaceful times,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For travelers by land, sea and air,
for the sick, the suffering,
index
captives and for their
salvation. Let us
pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For our deliverance from
all affliction, wrath, danger,
and distress, let us pray
to the Lord. Lord, have
mercy.
Help us, save us, have mercy
on us, and protect us, O God,
by your grace. Amen.
Remembering
our most holy, pure, blessed,
and glorious Lady, the Theodok
I'm so glad to be here.
and ever-Virgin Mary with all the saints,
let us commit ourselves and one another
and our whole life to Christ our God.
For to you belong all glory, honor, and worship
to the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit
now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
God is the Lord and...
He revealed Himself to us.
Blessed is He who comes in the name of the Lord.
All the nations surround us.
But in the name of the Lord I defended myself against them.
God is the Lord and He revealed Himself to us.
Blessed is He who comes in the name of the Lord.
When you descended unto death, O Lord, you who are immortal life,
put Hades to death by the lightning of your divinity.
And when you raised the dead from the netherworld,
all the hosts of heaven sang aloud to you,
O Christ, God, giver of life, glory to you.
Δόξα Πατρί και Υιό και Άγιο Πνεύματι, ότε κατήρθες προς τον θάνατον, η ζωή αθάνατος, τότε τον άδεινε νέκρος σας, τη άστραπη της θεότητος,
Ότε δε και τους τεθνεώτας εκ των κατακθονίων ανέστησας, πάσε δυναμή.
εις τον επουρανίον, εγκράβγαζον, ζώδωτα Χριστέ ο Θεός ημών, δόξα Συν.
Και νυν και αΐ και εις τους αιώνας των αιώνων, αμήν,
εν πίστη τους προπάτορας, εδικαίωσας,
την εξεθνών δι' αυτών προμνηστευσάμενος εκκλησίαν.
καυχόντε εν δόξη Άγιοι
ότι εξ πέρμαντος αυτών υπάρχει καρπός ευκλαιής, η ασπόρος θεκούσασε,
τε σ' αυτών η και εσύ εσχριστέ ο Θεός, σώσοντας ψυχάσιμο.
ΑΕΤΙ ΚΕΤΗ ΕΝ ΕΝΗΝΗ Του Κύριου ΔΕΙΘΟΜΕΡΙΗΣΟΝ
ΑΝτιλαβούς όσων ελέησων και διαφυλαξον ημάς
ο Θεός της ηχάριτης,
Κύριε Λέησον,
της Παναγίας Αχράτου,
υπερευλογημένης ενδόξου,
δεσποινήσιμον Θεοτόκου,
και αϊπαρθένου Μαρίας,
μεταπάντων των Αγίων
γημονεύσαντες,
εαυτούς και αλλήλους
και πάσα την ζωήν ημών,
Χριστό το Θεό
παραθώμεθα.
Συγκύριε
Ο της Σοντοκράτος και σου έστειν η Βασιλεία και η δύναμης και η δόξα του Πατρός και του Υιού και του Αγίου Πνεύματος νυν και αη και εις τους αιώνας των αιώνων.
Αμήν, ο Εύσχημον Ιωσήφ από του ξύλου καθελόν του άχραντών σου σώμα.
Συνδώνει καθαρά η λύστας και αρώμασιν, ενήματι και νόκυδεύσας απέθετο,
αλλά τριήμερος ανέστης Κύριε παρέχον το κόσμο το μεγαέλαιο.
Δόξα Πατρή και Υωκή Αγιοπνεύματι τες μυροφόρης γυνέξη παρά το μνήμα επιστά.
ο άγγελος ευώα, τα μοίρα της θνητής υπάρχει αρμόδια,
Χριστός δε διαφθόρας εδείχθη αλότριος,
αλλά κραυγάσατε ανέστη ο Κύριος, παρέχον το κόσμο το μεγαέλαιος.
Και νυν και αοικαίοι στους αιώνας των αιώνων, αμήν.
Πάντα υπερένειαν, πάντα υπερένδοξα τας αθεότο και μυστήρια,
η αγνία εσφραγισμένη και παρθενή αφυλατωμένη,
μη τήρε γνώστης αψεύδης θεών τεκούς αληθινών,
αυτόν η κέτευε σωθήν εντάς ψυχάσιμο.
Των λιθών του μνήματος φραγμένου
Αγίστην εμικολύσας, την πέτρα της πίστεως,
Αναστάς παρέσκη πάσης, Κύριε, δόξα Σύ.
Ωξα Πατρί και Υιώ και Αγίω Πνεύματι,
Τον μαθητών Σου ο χώρος συν μυροφόρης γίνεξε,
Να γάλετε συμφώνος, κινήν γαρεορτήν Συν αυτή σε ορτάζου,
εις δόξαν και τιμήν της εις αναστάσεως,
και δι' αυτόν φιλάνθρωπε Κύριε,
το λαό σου παράσκου το μεγαέλαιο.
Και νυν και αοικέεις τους αιώνας των αιώνων,
αμήν υπερευλογημένη υπάρχεις Θεοτό και παρθένε,
Διαγάρτου εξούς αρκωμένου
ο θέντος, ο άδης ηχμαλώτης ται, ο αδάμ ανάκαι κλητέ, η κατάραν νεκροτέ, η ευαϊνλευθέρωτε, ο θάνατος ται θανάτοτε,
και ημίσες ζωποιήθημεν δύο ανυμνούντες βόμεν ευλογητός Χριστός ο Θεός ημών
ο ούτως ευδοκής σας δόξα σύν.
Ευλογητός η Κύριε διδαξόν με τα δικαίωματά σου,
τον αγγέλων ο Δήμος κατεπλάγι ορών σε,
ενεκρής λογηστέντα του θάνατου δε σωτήρ την ισχύν καθελώντα,
και σ' ειναι αυτόν τον Αδά με Γύραντα
Εξάδου πάντας ελευθερός αντά.
Ευλογητός η Κύριε διδάξον με τα δικαιώματά σου,
τι τα μοίρας ημπαθος της δάκρυσην, ο μαθητριε κυρνάται,
ο αστράπτον εν το τάφο άγγελος προσευθέν και τότε σμυροφόρης.
Είδετε, είμείς των τάφων και είσθητε, ως ότι είστε.
Ρεξανέστη του μνήματον.
Ευλογητός η Κύριε διδαξον με τα δικαιωμάτα σου λείαν.
Πρωί μυροφόριε δραμον προς το μνήμα σου θρηνολογούσε.
Αλέπες τι προς αυτός ο άγγελος και είπε,
Τρινού ο καιρός π' αυτε μη πλέτε την Ανάσταση δε αποστολή.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Κύριε.
Αλληλούια, Αλληλούια, Αλληλούια, Δόξα σύ ο Θεός.
ΑΕΤΙΚΕΤΕΤΕΝ ΕΕΡΗΝΗ ΤΗ ΚΥΡΙΟ ΔΕΙΘΟΜΕΝ
ΚΥΡΙΗ ΕΛΕΙΣΟΝ
Σας ευχαριστώ.
Αυτός και λύλος και πάσαν την ζωήν ημών Χριστό το Θεό παραθώ μεθά.
Συ Κύριε.
Ότι ευλογητέ σου το όνομα και το δοξαστέ σου η Βασιλεία του Πατρός και του Υιού και του Άγιου Πνεύματος,
νυν και αϊκέις τους αιώνας των αιώνων.
Αμήν.
Μετά το πάθος πορευθείσαι εν το μνήματι, προς το μυρίσε το σώμα σου, εγυναίκες Χριστέ ο Θεός.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Είδω να γγέλουσεν το τάφο και εξέστησαν φωνείς γαρίκουον εξ αυτών, ότι ανέστη ο Κύριος παρέχον το κόσμο το μέγα έλεος.
Εν το ουρανό τα ώματα εκπέμπω μου της καρδίας προς εσωτείρους όσον με ση επιλάμψει.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Κι δώς προς θέλους τρόπους του μετανοήν Σοι.
Φόξα Πατρί και Υό και Άγιο Πνεύματι.
Δίν και Άγιο και Ιστους αιώνας των αιώνων αμήν.
Άγιο Πνεύματι το βασιλεύειν πέλη το Άγι Άζιν το Κινήν την κτίσην Θεός γαρεστήν,
ο Μαούσιος πατρί και λόγο
γυμιώτη Κύριος η Λόγωνα
Είναιν ημήν θυσικανός ως φυλακτήνε, εκ του εχθρού άμα και ανθρώποκτονου.
Ισοδούς ειν αυτόν μη παραδώσο τερ των σονβούλων, λέοντος τρόπον,
κατέ μου κινούνται και γάρι εχθροί μου.
Ω ξαπαδρή και ιό και Άγιο Πνεύματι,
και είν και αεί και εις τους αιώνας των αιών,
Αγίω πνευματίζω αρχή, χία και γέρας πάντα γάρτα κτιστά,
ως Θεός ον δύναμη συντηρεί εν πατρίδι ουδέ.
Υπεπιθώτες επί Κύριον, εήκα συνόρι το Αγίο,
Ιουδαμος αλεύονται προσβολές του βελία.
Ενώνομοι εσχύρασοι
Αγίος Αυτόν μη εκτινάτως ανηθίως όντες, ουγάρε α Χριστός τη ράβδο των κλήρων αυτού.
Ω ξαπατρί και Υιώ και Αγίω Πνεύματι και την Θεά η καίης τους αιώνας των αιώνων αμήν.
Καίοι ο Πνεύματι προσπηγάζει πάσα σοφία, ενθεν χάρις Αποστόλης και της άθλης κατάστασης.
τα στέφονται μάρτυρες και προφήται ορόσι.
Εξεγέρθητη Κύριε ο Θεός μου, εν προστάγματιό εν αιτήλο, και συναγωγή λαόν κυκλώσησε.
Again and again in peace let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
Help us, save us, have mercy on us,
and protect us, O God, by your grace.
Lord, have mercy.
Remembering our most holy, pure, blessed, and glorious
Lady Theothokos and ever-Virgin Mary
with all the saints,
let us commend ourselves and one another
and our whole life to Christ our God.
To you, O Lord.
For you are the King of peace and Saviour of our souls,
and to you we offer glory.
Glory to the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit,
now and forever and unto the ages of ages.
Amen.
Worshiping not the image made by hands,
but putting on the breastplate of the unwritten essence,
in the arena of fire you thrice-blessed ones were glorified.
Standing in the midst of a flame unendurable,
you called upon God.
Make haste, O compassionate one, and hurry as the merciful one unto our aid,
for you can do what you will.
Extend your hand, which of old the Egyptians, making battle,
and the Hebrews, then embattled, had experienced.
Do not forsake us, that death, who thirsts after us,
and Satan, who hates us, may drink us down.
But be near us and spare our souls, as you once spared your lads in Babylon,
as they see
ceaselessly sang your praises,
and were for you thrown into the furnace,
and from thence called to you.
Make haste, O compassionate one,
and hurry as the merciful one unto our aid.
For you can do what you will.
On the 14th of this month,
we commemorate the contest of the holy martyrs
Thyrsus, Lucius, and Kalinicus.
On this day, we commemorate the holy martyrs
Thank you.
Philemon, Apollyonos, Arianos, and those with them.
On this day we also commemorate the four guards
who contested together with Arianos.
On this day we also commemorate the great love
which was shown to us when we were delivered
from the fearful threat of earthquake by our benevolent Lord.
Today is also the Sunday of the Holy Forefathers.
By the intercessions of your saints, O God,
have mercy on us and save us. Amen.
Ananis.
Christ is born, glorify Him.
Christ is come from heaven, go and meet Him.
Christ is on earth, arise to Him.
Sing to the Lord, all you inhabitants of the world.
And all you peoples praise him, and with merriment extol him who is glorified.
To the Son begotten from the Father unchangingly before the ages,
and now becoming incarnate from the Virgin without sight.
To Christ God let us cry aloud,
You have exalted the horn of our strength,
Only you are holy, O Lord.
A rod has come forth from Jesse's root,
And you its flower grew from it.
Praiseworthy Christ, now born of the earth.
whom Habakkuk called Paran,
shady, thickly wooded mountain,
from her who knew no man you came incarnate.
O immaterial God, glory to your strength, O Lord.
O God of peace and Father of mercies,
You have sent.
to us the wonderful Counselor,
the angel of your great counsel,
granting us peace.
And now to light of knowledge
of God we have been guided,
and we rise from night to dawn
and glorify you, O benevolent Lord.
Lord.
Jonah long ago was hurled from the belly of the whale,
as he went in like a newborn babe with the virgin now,
when the logos had dwelt in his mother's womb.
Taking flesh, he then emerged, preserving her intact,
yielding not to a chance.
In changeability, he preserved her unaltered in childbirth.
Brought up together piously the servants,
With contempt regarded the impious king's decree.
The threat of the furnace did not frighten them,
Rather standing in the middle of the church.
midst of the flames they prayed and sang,
Blessed are you, O Lord God of our fathers.
We praise and we bless and we worship the Lord.
Babylon's bedoing furnace bore the image
of an extraordinary wonder.
For it did not burn the youths it was holding,
nor did the fire of divinity
consume the virgin's womb wherein it went.
And so let us songfully extol and praise.
Let all creation bless the Lord, sing I him to him,
and exalt him beyond man.
unto all the ages.
Let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For you, our God, are holy,
and you rest among the holy ones.
And to you we offer up glory
to the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit
now and forever.
you
And to the ages of ages.
Amen.
Let everything that breathes praise the Lord.
Pass up no ienesatot on Kyrian.
Let us pray to the Lord our God that we may be made worthy to hear the holy gospel.
Lord, have mercy, Lord.
Lord, have mercy, Lord, have mercy.
Wisdom arise, let us hear the Holy Gospel.
Peace be with you all.
And with your spirit.
The reading is from the Holy Gospel according to Luke.
Wisdom, let us be attentive.
Glory to you, O Lord, glory to you.
At that time, two of them were going to a village.
named Emmaus about seven miles from Jerusalem
and talking with each other
about all these things that had happened.
While they were talking and discussing together,
Jesus himself drew near and went with them.
But their eyes were kept from recognizing him,
and he said to them,
What is this conversation
which you are holding with each other as you walk?
And they stood still, looking sad.
Then one of them named Cleopas answered him,
Are you the only visitor to Jerusalem
who does not know
the things that have happened there in these days? And he said to them, What things? And they said to
him, Concerning Jesus of Nazareth, who was a prophet mighty in deed and word before God and all the
people, and how our chief priests and rulers delivered him up to be condemned to death and
crucified him. But we had hoped that he was the one to redeem Israel. Yes, and besides all this,
it is now the third day since this happened. Moreover, some women of our company amazed us.
they were
were at the tomb early in the morning and did not find his body. And they came back saying that they
had even seen a vision of angels who said that he was alive. Some of those who were with us went to
the tomb and found it just as the women had said, but him they did not see. And he said to them,
O foolish men and slow of heart to believe all that the prophets have spoken, was it not necessary
that the Christ should suffer these things
and enter into his glory?
And beginning with...
Moses and all the prophets, he interpreted to them and all the scriptures the things concerning
himself. So they drew near to the village to which they were going. He appeared to be going further,
but they constrained him, saying, Stay with us, for it is toward evening, and the day is now far
spent. So he went in to stay with them. When he was at table with them, he took the bread and
blessed and broken and gave it to them. And their eyes were opened, and they recognized him, and he
vanished out.
of their sight. They said to each other, Did not our hearts burn within us while he spoke to us on
the road, while he opened to us the scriptures? And they rose that same hour and returned to
Jerusalem, and they found the eleven gathered together, and those who were with them who said,
The Lord has risen indeed and has appeared to Simon. Then they told what had happened on the road.
and he was known to them in the breaking of the bread.
Glory to you, O Lord, glory to you.
Having beheld the resurrection of Christ,
let us worship the Holy Lord Jesus, the only sinless one.
Your cross, O Christ, we venerate,
and your holy resurrection we praise.
and glorify. For you are our God.
Apart from you we know no other.
We call upon your name. Come,
all faithful, let us venerate the
holy resurrection of Christ. For behold,
through the cross, joy has come to the whole
world. Ever blessing the Lord, let
us praise his resurrection. For having
endured the cross for us, he destroyed
death by death.
Have mercy on me, O God,
according to your great mercy
and according to the
abundance of your compassion.
Lord, not my transgression.
Wash me thoroughly from my lawlessness and cleanse me from my sin.
For I know my lawlessness and my sin is always before me.
Against you only have I sinned and done evil in your sight,
that you may be justified in your words.
And overcome when you are judged, for behold,
I was conceived in transgressions and in sin
my mother bore me.
Behold, you love truth.
You showed me the unknown and secret things of your wisdom.
You shall sprinkle me with hyssop and I will be cleansed.
You shall wash me and I will be made whiter than snow.
You shall make me hear joy and gladness.
My bones that were humbled shall greatly rejoice.
Turn your face from my sins
and blot out all my transgressions.
Create in me a clean heart, O God,
and renew a right spirit within me.
Do not cast me away from your presence
and do not take your Holy Spirit from me.
Restore me to the joy of your salvation
and uphold me with your guiding spirit.
I will teach transgressors your ways
and the ungodly shall turn back to you.
Deliver me from blood guiltiness.
O God, the God of my salvation, and my tongue shall greatly rejoice in your righteousness.
O Lord, you shall open my lips, and my mouth will declare your praise.
For if you desired sacrifice, I would give it.
You will not be pleased with whole burnt offerings.
A sacrifice to God is a broken spirit, a broken and humbled heart.
God will not despise
Do good, O Lord, in your good pleasure
Let the walls of Jerusalem be built.
Then you will be pleased with a sacrifice of righteousness,
with offerings and whole burnt offerings.
Then shall they offer young bulls on your altar
and have mercy on me, O God.
Glory to the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit
at the intercession of the...
apostles, O Lord of mercy, blot out my many offenses, both now and ever and to the ages
of ages.
Amen.
At the intercession of the Theotokos, O Lord of mercy, blot out my many offenses.
have mercy on me O God
according to your great mercy
according to the abundance of your compassion, blot out my transgression.
Jesus, having risen from the grave as he foretold, has granted us eternal life and great mercy.
He.
O God, save your people and bless your inheritance.
Look upon your world with mercy and compassion.
Raise the Orthodox Christians in glory
and send down upon us your rich mercies.
Through the intercessions of our all-immaculate Lady Theotokos,
an ever-virgin Mary,
by the power of the precious and life-giving cross,
the protection of the honorable heavenly bodiless powers,
the supplications of the honourable, glorious Prophet
and forerunner John the Baptist,
the holy, glorious, and praiseworthy apostles,
our fathers among the saints,
the great hierarchs and ecumenical teachers,
Basil the Great, Gregory the Theologian,
and John Chrysostom,
Athanasius, Cyril, and John the Merciful,
Patriarchs of Alexandria,
Nicholas, Bishop of Myra,
Spyridon, Bishop of Trimithus,
Nectarios of Pendapolis,
the Wonder Workers,
the holy glory
the glorious great martyrs, George the Triumphant,
Demetrius the Merced Dreamer, Theodore the Soldier,
Theodore the General, Minas the Wonder Worker,
Haralumbos and Elephterios, the holy priest martyrs,
the holy glorious and victorious martyrs,
the glorious great martyr and all audible Ephemia,
the holy and glorious martyrs, Thecla Barbara,
Anastasia Catherine, Kyriakie,
Fautini, Marina, Parasitia,
our venerable and God-bearing fathers,
the holy and righteous ancestors of God,
Joachim and Anna, and the holy forefathers
whose memory we observe, and all your saints.
We beseech you, only merciful Lord,
hear us, sinners who pray to you,
and have mercy on us.
Kyrie eleison, Kyrie eleison, Kyrie eleison,
Lord, have mercy, Lord, have mercy.
Lord, have mercy.
Kyrie eleison, kyrie eleison, kyrie eleison.
Through the mercies, compassion, and love for humankind
of your only begotten Son, with whom you are blessed,
and your all-holy good.